<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-07T07:05:04+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kohde.io</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">RP Africa Employee self service</title><link href="/2021/07/12/rp-africa-employee-self-service-app.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RP Africa Employee self service" /><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/07/12/rp-africa-employee-self-service-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/07/12/rp-africa-employee-self-service-app.html">&lt;p&gt;RP Africa Fleet Services operates in eight countries across the African continent and cross border Fleet Management Services. RP Africa’s cross border drivers are key to the management of fleets across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing over 1500 drivers and more than 20 customers, RP Africa Fleet Services partnered with Kohde to develop a unique fleet management platform. The new platform will assist RP Africa with:
Employee onboarding.
Reducing administration related to storing, organising and locating critical employee related information. 
Easily identify suitable candidates based on a customer’s transport and logistic requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RP Africa extended some platform features to their employees via a mobile application. This will further reduce unnecessary admin by enabling their employees to view and update their own information and documentation while keeping all stakeholders informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;float:left; max-width: 48%; display: inline-block;&quot;&gt;
 The RP Africa and Kohde teams worked together closely using an iterative approach. Collaboratively, the team identified core features which were first prototyped. This allowed the team to move quickly in the early stages of the project. 
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  During the development phase, the team followed a similar approach using CI/CD pipelines which allowed us to deploy and review regularly. This allowed RP Africa to start working on the platform within three months of project commencement and provide feedback on required changes.We are looking forward to continuing this journey with RP Africa, and further enabling their customers and employees through technology.
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kohde-rp-article-image.png&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;float:right; max-width: 52%; display: inline-block; &quot; /&gt;    
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">RP Africa Fleet Services operates in eight countries across the African continent and cross border Fleet Management Services. RP Africa’s cross border drivers are key to the management of fleets across Africa.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-rp.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-rp.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Table Charm E-commerce site</title><link href="/2021/07/12/table-charm-ecommerce-site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Table Charm E-commerce site" /><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/07/12/table-charm-ecommerce-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/07/12/table-charm-ecommerce-site.html">&lt;p&gt;Table Charm Direct is one of the fastest growing direct selling companies in Southern Africa. Helping thousands of people supplement their income and become financially independent, since 1974.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Table Charm Direct’s continuous drive to go-digital and the goal to introduce streamlined revenue streams into the business, they approached Kohde to assist them with launching their ecommerce solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kohde-tablecharm-article-image.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: 20px&quot; /&gt;
     The team’s engagement started with various workshops to identify key problem areas and to identify where the most and immediate value can be added. We used Opensource to deploy to production quickly. Using Opensource also allows us to focus on the business problem, while still mitigating the risk of vendor lock in and licencing fees. All businesses have custom processes that make them unique, and to fill these gaps we used custom development. Some of this where.
     &lt;ul style=&quot;padding-left: 560px;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Synchronizing orders directly into Table Charm Directs ERP system.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Integration with courier service providers to automatically book and trace parcels and deliveries.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A customer can now pay directly with the shop.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Keeping customers informed with sms notification.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The team deployed the first version of the ecommerce platform within the first month and also performed a lift and shift of the existing systems from an on premise hosting environment to a cloud based environment.   
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With the new ecommerce platform, Table Charm Direct is able to increase their product to consumer turnaround, better serving their distributors and their customers.  
 
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Table Charm Direct is one of the fastest growing direct selling companies in Southern Africa. Helping thousands of people supplement their income and become financially independent, since 1974.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/kohde-tablecharm-top-image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/kohde-tablecharm-top-image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Axiz Project</title><link href="/2020/07/11/axiz-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Axiz Project" /><published>2020-07-11T07:37:59+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T07:37:59+00:00</updated><id>/2020/07/11/axiz-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/07/11/axiz-project.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Axiz required an online integratable digital platform in order to keep up with current ever evolving software technologies. The solution they require is one that can integrate with big vendor players such as Microsoft CSP, CISCO, IBM, HPE to name a few and seamlessly integrate back into Axiz’s on premise ERP. Before Axiz decided to custom develop a solution, they’ve researched different software solution providers in order to ascertain if there is a product or service off the shelf that will facilitate such a wide variety of vendor market integrations and products on a single digital platform. Due to the scale of and multiple software procurement, customization and licensing fees that would be required it was decided to custom develop the digital platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first step of engagement was to understand the problem they are facing and the vision they had of where they wanted to go then created high fidelity prototypes to find the best way to solve complex problems, simply. The challenge was to find the common base features that could be used across all vendor brands or even more if the commonality exists. AVA (Axiz Virtual Assistant) was thus developed as the core integration facilitator between the multiple vendor digital platform integrations and the solution is built on a microservice architecture whilst leveraging off a boilerplate platform. This allowed Axiz to scale their digital footprint into current integratable vendor platforms as well as future proof in the event that other vendors follow suit to go digital.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Challenge</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-axiz.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-axiz.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Continual Logistics</title><link href="/2020/07/11/continual-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Continual Logistics" /><published>2020-07-11T07:37:59+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T07:37:59+00:00</updated><id>/2020/07/11/continual-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/07/11/continual-project.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client wished to create a platform that would form a bridge between businesses who seek to transport goods and those who transport them. Specifically the client wished to unburden their coordinators of the time-consuming and error-prone manual processes involved in coordinating freight logistics. This includes locating vendors who have the correct vehicles to maintain product grade, as well as making sure that the correct authorizations are provided to the correct drivers for the appropriate locations. Typically this coordination would involve numerous phone calls, emails, and sharing of documents that might look different from one day to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team was challenged to create several powerful interfaces within one unified system, including one that would allow coordinators to petition verified transportation vendors for work required, and also allow for detailed route and load planning, with a high degree of flexibility to update these in response to real-life events. The aim was to remove as much manual data capturing as possible by integrating with third-party systems to ensure that all financial and operational data is consolidated into one fully audited system, allowing coordinators to respond quickly to events such as vehicle breakdowns, and rest assured that a complete paper trail is maintained for all planned and rendered services.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Challenge</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-continual.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-continual.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Afgri Grain Management</title><link href="/2020/07/11/afgri-grain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Afgri Grain Management" /><published>2020-07-11T07:37:59+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T07:37:59+00:00</updated><id>/2020/07/11/afgri-grain</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/07/11/afgri-grain.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was facing multiple challenges in which they continuously found themselves performing manual and time consuming tasks each month. The list varied from keeping track of which assets required maintenance to keeping track of what time workers spent on maintaining these assets. The list also extended to managing and overseeing all the various costs involved. The managing and consolidation of these administrative tasks became a huge burden and so the client decided to venture into the market to find a solution that fulfilled their business needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solution was built and provided to alleviate the administrative burden in allowing the workers to be able to take on some of the administrative responsibility. The workers were given the capability of logging faults on machinery, requesting quote approvals from head office on asset repairs that were required and approved quotation would automatically generate a purchase order directly from SAP. Workers were able to seamlessly and without effort log and record all time spent at various sites and the client was able to easily manage and keep track of all workers. The new application (mobile and web), massively reduced the amount of time the client spent on performing and maintaining various administrative tasks and duties.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Challenge</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-afgri.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-afgri.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trigga Trader</title><link href="/2020/05/16/trigga-bidding-platform.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trigga Trader" /><published>2020-05-16T07:37:59+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-16T07:37:59+00:00</updated><id>/2020/05/16/trigga-bidding-platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/05/16/trigga-bidding-platform.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigga Traders in an online platform created to ensure fair and transparent trading in the agricultural market. Trigga allows sellers and agricultural commodities to engage in a fair market place and in essence ensure to make agricultural trading easier. We were approached by Trigga to partner in their mission to facilitate fair exchange. Our team was tasked with redesign and architecture of the Trigga platform to ensure that it is transparent, scalable, and user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the buyer and seller experience at heart, we took on the task of creating a bespoke platform that would enhance the bidding experience. This could not have been achieved if we did not include key Trigga team members in the decision-making process. We remained in constant communication with the operational and marketing members of Trigga to ensure we meet the user’s needs. This included catering for the scheduling, implementation, and execution of multiple auctions. Organizing an auction on the scale that Trigga does, requires high-level management of a large amount of commodity and seller specific data. The Trigga platform was built to host all the needed data in one place and ensure that an auction could run seamlessly from creation to execution. This included creating a database of buyers and sellers while keeping fair and responsible exchange in mind. Part of enhancing the user experience was to generate excitement during a live auction. The Trigga platform was designed with the intent to provide the same amount of excitement that bidder would experience during a real-life auction. We achieved this by including visual cues inspired by game theory. This included visually representing the number of bidders partaking in an auction and when a bid is placed and through micro animations. Along with enhancing the bidding experience our team also took on the task of creating a scalable platform. Ensuring that it could cater to different types of users, auctions, and commodities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Challenge</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-trigga.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/kohde-projects-showcase-image-trigga.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>